Contact

+55 21 98847-2727 (Mobile) jorgedoriajr@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/jorge-viana-doria-junior-m-sc-64970615 (LinkedIn) github.com/jorgedoriair (Portfolio)

Top Skills

Geographic Information Systems (GIS)

Domain-Driven Design (DDD)

Java Application Development

Languages

Espanhol (Full Professional)
English (Full Professional)
Portuguese (Native or Bilingual)

Certifications

Inteligência Emocional
Professional Scrum Master
Professional Scrum Product Owner
Negociação e Influência

Honors-Awards
OKR Award 2023

Publications

Analyzing the Incremental Funding Method and its Software Project Scheduling Algorithms.

Towards a Novel Statistical Method for Generating Test Sets with a Given Coverage Probability

On the Merits and Pitfalls of the Incremental Funding Method and its Software Project Scheduling Algorithms

Identifying the Most Efficient Implementation Sequence of IT Projects Broken Down into MMFs and AEs

Jorge Viana Doria Junior, M.Sc.

Software Architect | Back-end Developer | Java | Spring Boot |
RabbitMQ | Apache Kafka | Kubernetes | Docker | AWS | ReactJS |
TypeScript | GraphQL | PSM® | PSPO® | SAFe® Agilist
Rio de Janeiro, Brazil

Summary

Master's degree in Computer Science from the Institute of Mathematics and Computer Science Department of iNCE/PPGI/UFRJ in 2013. Postgraduated in Systems Analysis, Project, and Management by PUC-Rio in 2006. Postgraduated in Management of Technology in Computing at UFF in 2002. I have 20 years of experience as a software engineer in various industries, including healthcare, retail, banking, and oil and gas. During this time, I spent nearly a decade as a Senior Systems Analyst and IT Project Manager at Petrobras Transportes S/A - Transpetro. My expertise is in Computer Science, with a focus on Information Systems, specializing in Software Engineering topics such as Risk Analysis, Process Modeling, Business Rules, IT Strategy Preparation and Analysis, IT Investment Analysis, Economics of Software Engineering, Strategic IT Management, Agile Methodologies, and Management of High-Complexity Projects.

Currently, I am seeking a managerial or technical position in software engineering, such as Senior Back-end Developer, Software Architect or Software Project Manager.

Experience

FIAP

Professor

July 2023 - Present (9 months)

São Paulo, Brasil

Professor of the Postgraduate courses POS TECH in Software Architecture and Java Architecture and Development in the evening from 7 p.m. to 10 p.m.

Mooven Consulting Senior System Analyst March 2021 - January 2024 (2 years 11 months) São Paulo, Brasil

I've worked on building client software products and new business solutions.

Impulse Soluções e Consultoria Senior Software Engineer January 2022 - October 2022 (10 months) São Paulo, Brazil

Responsible for maintaining the following retail solutions, in partnership with JDAGILE TECNOLOGIA LTDA - CNPJ 46.906.906/0001-70:

- 1. ERP Gestão-Televendas, a solution built in Java Swing and used by pharmacies for delivery.
- 2. LINX.IO, an API developed in Java Spring Boot and Netflix Eureka to integrate channels (ERP and E-Commerce) with operators.
- 3. ITEC-SUITE, the AngularJS front-end designed for managing products in e-commerce.
- 4. WEBCONVENIO-SERVICE, the back-end developed in Java Spring Boot and Netflix Eureka for managing products in e-commerce.

BRQ Digital Solutions Senior System Analyst June 2019 - March 2021 (1 year 10 months) Rio de Janeiro, Brasil

I've worked on building client software products and new business solutions.

Centro Universitário Carioca Professor January 2014 - June 2020 (6 years 6 months) Rio de Janeiro, Brasil

Professor in the disciplines that are part of the graduation curriculum of the Computer Science course, such as: Algorithms I, Algorithms II, Introduction to Programming, Structured Programming, Data Structure, Systems Analysis and Project, Database I, Database II, Project Management, Concepts of Object Orientation, Object-Oriented Programming, Database Application Development, Distributed Application Development, Web Application Development, Mobile Application Development, Requirements Engineering, Network Fundamentals, Scientific Methodology, Programming Language Models, Computer Science Integrative Project, Information Security, Operating Systems, Computer Science Monograph, Software Engineering Theory,

Software Quality, and Advanced Topics in System Development. Participation in the monograph and orientation of some students.

Professor of the Postgraduate and MBA courses in Project Management, such as: Cost Management, Time Management, Risk Management and Procurement, Modeling and Management of Business Processes, Enterprise Architecture and Special Topics in Innovation in Organizations (Agile Project Management with Scrum, Kanban, Scaled Agile Framework - SAFe, Team Building Practices and Management 3.0).

FACULDADES SÃO JOSÉ

Professor

January 2019 - June 2019 (6 months)

Rio de Janeiro, Brasil

Professor of the discipline that is part of the graduation curriculum of the Information Systems Technology course: Emerging Topics in Information Technology (Development of Hybrid Mobile Applications).

Spread Tecnologia Software Architect November 2018 - June 2019 (8 months) Rio de Janeiro

Responsible for Software Architecture during the maintenance of a web and mobile banking system.

The technologies used were as follows:

HTML5, Bootstrap, JavaScript ES6, TypeScript, AngularJS, Angular Material, Ionic 5, Cordova 9, ReactJS, Redux, React Native, Node.js, Java EE, EJB 3.0/2.1, RESTful WebServices, GraphQL, GraphCMS, Apollo GraphQL, Apache Maven, JBoss (WildFly), Jenkins, Swagger, Sonatype Nexus, SonarQube, Elasticsearch, Oracle, SQL Server Database and MongoDB.

Furthermore, I have knowledge of Docker with Docker File, Docker Compose, Docker Hub and Docker Network, Java Spring Boot (Spring Data JDBC, Spring Data JPA, Spring Data MongoDB, Spring HATEOAS, Spring Cloud, Spring Security, Spring Session, Spring Batch, Spring Intregation, Spring WebFlux, Flyway Maven Plugin and Hexagonal Architecture and Microservices), Asynchronous Processing with Queues in RabbitMQ and ActiveMQ and Spring Boot, container orchestration system with Kubernetes

for automating software deployment, scaling, and management, experience in developing unit tests with Mockito Framework, stress test with K6 and functional tests Selenium WebDriver, Clean Code and Design Patterns practice.

Instituto Infnet
Professor
January 2017 - April 2018 (1 year 4 months)
Rua São José, 90 - Centro, Rio de Janeiro - CEP 20010-020

Professor in the disciplines that are part of the graduation curriculum of the Information Systems course (Business and Management) at the Business School, such as: Object Orientation with UML (Data Modeling), Fundamentals of Java Development, Object Orientation with Java, Java EE Development, Java Web Development, Fundamentals of Java Development: Android, Frontend Frameworks (AngularJS) with Back-end connection (Node.js), Relational Data Modeling, Oracle SQL and PL/SQL.

Tecnenge Tecnologia De Enga Ltda IT Project Manager November 2012 - July 2017 (4 years 9 months) Rio de Janeiro, Brasil

I worked at Transpetro S/A and participated in Agile Project Management using the Scrum framework with the software factory Sonda IT. During the IT Project Portfolio Management with leadership, I was responsible for receiving the demands of the company's professionals, who often had little knowledge of technology and almost always had little time to explain what they needed. I knew the business deeply and had the ability to quickly identify the client's needs, even when it was not clearly articulated. Furthermore, I was able to propose solutions that might not have occurred to the customer, as well as immediately evaluate the impacts of what was being requested business processes of the organization and properly aligned with the strategic objectives of the company.

Universidade Gama Filho Professor March 2012 - February 2014 (2 years) Rio de Janeiro, Brasil

Professor of the following subjects: Software Engineering II, Distributed Systems, Guided Study in Computing, Web Programming (ASP.NET), Database I, Programming I (VB.NET) and Programming II (VISUAL C#.NET)

which are part of the graduation curriculum of the Computer Science course. Participation in the monograph and orientation of some students.

UniverCidade - Centro Universitário da Cidade do Rio de Janeiro Professor

March 2012 - February 2014 (2 years)

Rio de Janeiro, Brasil

Professor of the following subjects: Software Engineering, Systems Modeling and Project, and Introduction to Computing that are part of the graduation curriculum of the Computer Science, Information Systems, and Systems Analysis and Development courses. Participation in the monograph and orientation of some students.

Concremat Engenharia e Tecnologia Senior Systems Analyst December 2007 - November 2012 (5 years) Rio de Janeiro, Brasil

I worked at Transpetro S/A and participated in the analysis and development project of the geographic information system on pipeline integrity - GIS TRANSPETRO.

Technologies: Autodesk Mapguide 2012, Google Earth, Oracle Spacial 11g, ASP.NET, C# 4.0 and Enterprise Library.

Banco BOCOM BBM Senior Systems Analyst February 2007 - November 2007 (10 months) Rio de Janeiro, Brasil

Responsible for the maintenance of the bank's investment funds management systems, in partnership with the company N2 Informática Ltda. Technologies: advanced use of T-SQL language with SQL Server 2000 (Stored Procedures) and Visual Basic 6.0 development languages using COM+.

I participated in projects in the investment fund area of the BBM bank as a developer of the Quota System. I worked in the bank's treasury system, just the money laundering (fraud) monitoring and prevention system and the CLP system (risk assessment in the Credit Line Proposal) for customers with high economic profitability.

Ibrowse Consultoria e Informática Senior Systems Analyst September 2006 - January 2007 (5 months)

Page 5 of 8

Rio de Janeiro, Brasil

Responsible for the development of the hospital management systems for a Federal Hospital in Rio de Janeiro. The technologies used were the following: advanced use of SQL language with SQL Server 2000, Delphi 6.0 development IDE, Object Pascal Language and Java Technologies:

- Java EE Architecture in Monolithic MVC and Microservices Projects;
- Apache Tomcat and JBOSS/WildFly Application Servers (Oracle Weblogic and/or Websphere valued);
- Experience developing with Java/Jakarta EE (JPA, EJB 3, JMS) or Spring;
- Experience in SOAP and REST Werbservices in technologies such as JAX-WS, JAX-RS, JSON RPC, among others;
- Knowledge of database persistence (JDBC, JPQL, JPA, Hibernate and EclipseLink);
- Knowledge in Oracle, SQL Server, MySQL and/or PostgreSQL;
- Knowledge of code version control tools (SVN and/or GIT)
- Knowledge of CI/CD tools with GitLab;
- Knowledge of Apache Maven;
- Experience in User Interface implementations (HTML5 and CSS3).
- Experience in Java Server Faces (JSF);
- Experience in developing unit, integration and functional tests;
- Clean Code and Design Patterns practice.

Centro Universitário UniCarioca

Professor

January 2005 - December 2006 (2 years)

Rio de Janeiro, Brasil

Professor of the disciplines: Structured Algorithms, Object-Oriented Analysis, Object-Oriented Project and Java that are part of the graduation curriculum of the Information Systems Technology courses. Participation in the monograph and orientation of some students.

Estácio

Professor

May 2004 - December 2006 (2 years 8 months)

Rio de Janeiro, Brasil

Professor in the Systems Analysis course where I lectured the subject: Information Systems.

Tecnocoop Sistemas Cooperativa de Trabalho dos Profissionais de Processamento de Dados LTDA

Senior Systems Analyst

April 2004 - September 2006 (2 years 6 months)

Rio de Janeiro, Brasil

Responsible for the development of the hospital management systems for a Federal Hospital in Rio de Janeiro. The technologies used were the following: advanced use of SQL language with SQL Server 2000, Delphi 6.0 development IDE, Object Pascal Language and Java Technologies:

- Java EE Architecture in Monolithic MVC and Microservices Projects;
- Apache Tomcat and JBOSS/WildFly Application Servers (Oracle Weblogic and/or Websphere valued);
- Experience developing with Java/Jakarta EE (JPA, EJB 3, JMS) or Spring;
- Experience in SOAP and REST Werbservices in technologies such as JAX-WS, JAX-RS, JSON RPC, among others;
- Knowledge of database persistence (JDBC, JPQL, JPA, Hibernate and EclipseLink);
- Knowledge in Oracle, SQL Server, MySQL and/or PostgreSQL;
- Knowledge of code version control tools (SVN and/or GIT)
- Knowledge of CI/CD tools with GitLab;
- Knowledge of Apache Maven;
- Experience in User Interface implementations (HTML5 and CSS3).
- Experience in Java Server Faces (JSF);
- Experience in developing unit, integration and functional tests;
- Clean Code and Design Patterns practice.

OneSysttem

Systems Programmer

June 2003 - March 2004 (10 months)

Rio de Janeiro, Brasil

Responsible for the maintenance of OneLoja's commercial automation systems: Backoffice, Cashier and Pre-Sale. The technologies used were: advanced use of SQL language with SQL Server 2000, report creation through Crystal Reports 10.0 and programming language: Visual Basic 6.0 using COM +.

Analysis Group Negocios e Participacoes Ltda IT Consultant

April 2001 - April 2003 (2 years 1 month)

Rio de Janeiro, Brasil

Responsible for the IT Department.

Tribunal de Justiça do Estado do Rio de Janeiro Legal Expert in Informatics January 2001 - December 2002 (2 years)

Rio de Janeiro, Brasil

Signatory, REPRESENTATIVE JUDICIAL EXPERT, appointed in case no. 2001.209.005242-0 "Preventive Action for Search and Apprehension of Software", in which the claimant is Marcos Ferreira Mendonça and the defendant SAFETY STOP Planejamento e Assessoria Ltda, of the 2nd Civil Court of the City of Barra da Tijuca, State of Rio de Janeiro.

Education

Federal University of Rio de Janeiro

Master's degree, Computer Science · (March 2012 - October 2013)

Pontifícia Universidade Católica do Rio de Janeiro

Postgraduate in Systems Analysis, Design and Management, Information Systems · (January 2005 - December 2006)

Universidade Federal Fluminense

Postgraduate in Management of Technology in Computing, Information Systems · (August 2001 - July 2002)

UNIABEU

Undergraduate degree, Information Technology · (August 1996 - December 1999)